Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/caraseganti-95b444b5 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing Healthcare Hospitals

Certifications

BLS PALS CCRN ACLS

Cara Seganti

DNP, RN, CCRN

Greater New York City Area

Summary

Experienced Registered Nurse with a demonstrated history of working in the Surgical Intensive Care Unit. Currently a Student Registered Nurse Anesthetist in the DNP Nurse Anesthesia Program at Rutgers University and am scheduled to graduate May 2020.

Experience

Northwell Health Registered Nurse March 2012 - August 2019 (7 years 6 months) Surgical Intensive Care Unit

- -Provides care for critically ill patients in the SICU, as well as float to the CTICU, MICU, and CCU, when necessary.
- -Acts as Charge Nurse of SICU's 13 bed unit, coordinating care for patients through effective communication with multiple disciplines; delegates nursing assignments; oversees admissions and discharges; advocates for peer nurses, patients, and patient's family members.
- -Code Blue Team and Rapid Response Team responding member
- -Magnet Champion of SICU for NSLIJ's Magnet Committee
- -Skills include management of arterial lines, central venous catheters, chest tubes, mechanical ventilators, titration of vasopressors drips, insulin drips, and other various medication administration, Continuous Renal Replacement Therapy, Continuous Bladder Irrigation, ECG interpretation, phlebotomy, conscious sedation, ICP monitoring, ventriculostomy and lumber drain devices, assisting MDs with intubation and other various procedures.
- -Proficient in the Sunrise Clinical Manager System for computerized patient charting

I.U.O.E. Local 14-14B Administrative Assistant May 2008 - March 2012 (3 years 11 months)

-Created and organized an electronic filing system, as well as a backup system to maintain and securely retain documents.

- -Bookkeeping (Accounts Payable & Accounts Receivable) and data entry
- -Assisted members, answered phones, reception, and other various clerical duties.

Winthrop-University Hospital
Patient Care Associate
May 2009 - February 2012 (2 years 10 months)

- -Performs various patient care activities and related services necessary in caring for the personal needs, comfort, and safety of the patient with consideration to their age and cultural background.
- -Carries out job activities under the direct supervision of the registered nurse and performs certain duties as delegated.
- -Proactive in maintaining a clean and orderly environment.

Education

Rutgers University

Doctor of Nursing Practice- DNP, Nurse Anesthetist · (2017 - 2020)

Molloy College

Bachelor of Science (BS), Nursing · (2008 - 2011)